# IGCSE English Teacher Head of the English Department

#### CHRISTINA FAYEZ NEMR AZIZ

+0020-122-552-9368 (Calls and SMS) +44 7564 741581(SMS only) El Khalifa El Maamoun, Roxy, Heliopolis Cairo, Egypt ue0rsq@sunderland.ac.uk christina.azizz@gmail.com

## **Personal Statement:**

I have held several positions, including Head of the English Department and GCSE English teacher. My primary focus has been creating a learning environment that significantly impacts student achievement. My role involves instructing students on the GCSE syllabus provided by CAIE, Edexcel, and Oxford AQA to facilitate their goal-reaching process. Additionally, I serve as an English academic tutor at The University of Sunderland, UK. My educational qualifications, which include a master's in education (MED), QTS and PGCE, coupled with my practical teaching experience in mainstream education, have equipped me with the requisite knowledge and skills to provide high-quality leadership and teaching services.

### Education

# **University of Sunderland**

- -Master's degree in international education (MED)
- -QTS
- -PGCE
- -Ain Shams University
- -Bachelor of English Arts Faculty of Arts
- -Major: English Literature and Language
- -Ramses College for Girls (RCG) Ex. American College for Girls
- English instructor at the University of Sunderland, UK
- Head of the English Department
- Academic Coordinator
- Google certified educator
- IGCSE A/AS English Literature/Language teacher
- IGCSE English teacher (Extended and Core)
- IB DP English Literature and Language teacher
- AP English Literature/Language and Composition teacher
- Cambridge Year 8-Checkpoint English Language Teacher
- IELTS instructor
- Professional Development leader
- A member of the school's Technology Committee

Christina Fayez Aziz

IGCSE English Teacher Head of the English Department

2019-Present

Cairo, Egypt

## **Work Experience:**

The University of Sunderland, The United Kingdom 2021-2022

**English Instructor** 

**Capital International Schools (CIS)** 

IGCSE English teacher

English and Social Studies Head of Departments

Academic Coordinator

PYP and Pre-DP academic coordinator

Professional Development member

Academic Coordinator

Member of the technology committee

Member of the accreditation team

AP English teacher

**British Ramses School (BRS)** 

**2017-2019 Cairo, Egypt** 

2010-2017

Cairo, Egypt

IGCSE English teacher (Core and Extended)

## Saint Fatima British International – Nasr City

- Head of the English Department

- A/AS Level English Language teacher
- IGCSE English Language teacher (Core and Extended)
- KS3 English Language Teacher
- AP English Language and Composition teacher
- SAT English teacher
- A member of the school's Professional Development Committee

# Certificates, courses and pieces of training

- Extension Cambridge IGCSE English as a Second Language (0510-0511) (0991-0993)
  Syllabus (course conducted by Cambridge Assessment International Education)
- Marking Workshop Cambridge IGCSE English as a Second Language0510-0511) (0991-0993) Syllabus (course conducted by Cambridge Assessment International Education)
- IB 'Reflect-Teach' workshop with Dr Aliki Costantinou in The International School of Elite
- Cambridge Lower Secondary training and workshops international and Trans-Regional
- Numerous training sessions with the British Council
- Cognitive-Behavioural Therapy CBT
  - New ways of looking at old problems: a solution focused approach Course- University of Sunderland
  - Am I good enough? Navigating Impostor Phenomenon Course- University of Sunderland
  - CSDP01 Cyber Security & Data Protection-University of Sunderland
  - Equality, Diversity & Inclusion Portal- University of Sunderland
- I have been providing numerous Professional Development programmes across my teaching career.

### Co-curricular activities I have led in my previous and current positions:

- Drama
- Community Service

# Christina Fayez Aziz

IGCSE English Teacher Head of the English Department

- Technology based learning
- English Club
- Competitions

# **Computer Skills:**

 Perfect knowledge of Apple Education System, Microsoft Office, various programmes for LMS, CLG, and creating websites/ blogs.

# **Language Skills:**

English: Fluent in written and spoken French: Very good written and spoken

Arabic: Native Language Latin: Fair knowledge

# • Other Skills:

Reading, painting, tennis, cycling and swimming.

#### Reference:

Numerous referees can be provided upon request.